All right. Welcome back, everyone.
So,
so here I want to talk just a little bit
about mob programming because it's a tool
that I'd like to use through the through
parts of the course where we're doing
some significant development and it will
be useful I think to collaborate on this.
Um, so.
Let me first just talk about.
Um.
What this is basically,
raise your hand if you have any
experience doing mob programming.
Um. So what it is is basically um.
It's a way of collaborating on a on a
solution.
Started out basically with everybody in
the same room. You'd have one computer,
one person would sit at the computer and
drive the process,
and everybody else would.
Every everybody else would either provide
support for the person or drive the the
actual process and determine what needs
to be done next.
So the the idea is we divvy up the
responsibilities for the work session to
the person who's driving.
A a person who's navigating and then us
people that are supporting the navigator
in terms of research or anything else
that might be needed to to keep the
process moving.
The benefit of this is that everybody
participates in in in in all of these
roles by just.
Everybody's familiar with the code that
gets created,
and it's a great way of collaborating
together on solving a particular problem.
Here, what it's going to help us with is.
Essentially allowing us to distribute the
work and to work together remotely on the
building out a a a solution. So so yeah,
as I said, yeah,
cogeneration is non deterministic.
As an old saying,
a man with one watch always knows the
time a man with two watches is never sure,
which I think applies here because
because we have a lot of,
we have a lot of different responses
coming back from a I related to the
prompts that we're working on.
We'll spend a lot of time trying to
understand what those differences are
rather than focusing on the task at hand,
which is to keep the project moving
forward. So if you haven't tried it,
I've found it to be a worse useful
technique.
I think it's particularly gonna be useful
here.
And so instead of working alone,
let's work together on building some
software. As I said,
it started with one person working on one
machine and we rotate through that and
remote modding the team shares a a work
in a work in progress branch.
So what the mob dot SH solves is the is
is basically the suit smooth trend off
head off during pair rotation.
It deals handles the work in progress
branches.
It has a timer built in so that we can
keep track of time and then it does the
cleaning up a commit merges at the end
and it works with any the git provider,
so it's a fairly.
uh useful tool no matter what environment
you happen to be in.
So installing mob dot SH.
So this is has anybody had a question on
on the installation portion?
Raise your hand if you have any issues
with it.
All right,
so I'm going to assume then that we all
have it working.
So basically this is the installation
instructions.
What I want to go on and talk about then
is how do we use this.
But before we get into that,
I want to make sure everybody has cloned
this repo because this will be where our
work in progress branches are going to be.
Restored.
So let's go ahead and make sure that's
done.
Um.
So, yeah, Chris.
Do we have a link to the repo?
If you do a search for AIASD dash 260209,
it'll pop up.
John John Miller at Codemag Dashcom.
That's the one.
OK. And and just a heads up,
you're sharing your presentation screen
and not just the slides.
Oh, you're right. Thank you.
Yeah.
All right.
Anybody need time to clone the repo?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm not finding the link myself.
Do you have a direct URL that you could
paste in?
Sure.
Is anybody else getting 500 errors on
GitHub?
Seems to be back up.
Well, I got an error.
I've been getting intermittent, you know,
those Unicorn errors throughout the
morning on.
GitHub has been having issues all morning.
Our developers have been posting about
that.
Yeah,
I couldn't connect to GitHub at all
during the last session,
but it's it's working for me now.
Yeah, that would be a problem.
I.
Uh.
Also getting uh 500 errors back in
copilot.
Yeah, thanks, Chris, for posting the link.
Raise your hand if you you got to clone
the repo.
It's still trying to do it for me.
500 error here too.
Using CLI says cloning in progress,
no feedback yet.
Back in.
Try it again and successful here.
Uh, John, sorry, uh, maybe I missed that.
Where is the link to the repo?
It's in the teams chat.
In the chat.
Don't see that in the chat for some
reason. Don't know why.
Can you put that again? OK, thank you.
Got it. Thanks.
Yeah.
But.
Anybody making progress?
I I haven't been able to get it down
since,
but on GitHub status page there is a
report of incident with issues,
actions and get operations.
All right,
looks like Tom was able to get it.
I was able to get it with git command
line,
but it didn't work with Visual Studio.
It's getting like a 500,
but I just use the command line.
Get clone and then the URL.
Who still doesn't have it?
Raise your hand.
Yeah, I'm getting stuck at, uh, cloning.
I I got stuck once and then I closed the
window and started the new window and it
worked.
So I only saw two folks that are are
still working on their clone.
So I think we can move forward with what
we have and.
And give you guys a little bit more time
to get the clone working.
So we'll probably put you at the end of
the list for the mob. So,
so this is how this works.
This is basically a a UI.
For this as well as a.
Command line so you can go into the
terminal and you can type a mob start
once you have the application running and
that will start a new mob session.
The idea is that when we start that new
mob session that will create a work in
progress branch.
Stash any local changes that you might
have and then open our editor and
potentially start a new timer.
So we do this just once.
We just have to start one session and
then and then everybody can essentially.
Uh, join that session.
So when you go to the next driver,
we do a command called mob next and what
that will do is commit to this work in
progress branch that's been created and
then pushes to the remote so that the
next person can pull the work in progress
branch and and they can start and we can
start on the next session.
For the next iteration,
when we're finished with the mob session,
we would then do a mob done,
which will squash in our work in progress
commit and merge them to our main branch
and then clean up that work in progress
branch.
So it's pretty it's fairly simple if we
go into Visual Studio code.
UI elements it's the.
Mm.
So over here is our our mob start to
shrink things down a little bit to see
the rest of this and over here is a mob
next for the next turn and then we have
some utilities.
For starting and stopping a a timer if we
want need to do that so we can then say
start.
And it looks like it wants to do
something with these uncommitted changes,
so I will.
And do those.
Now we'll start it again.
And.
We can start the timer.
So we would set the timer in minutes,
do something like um.
Got 3 minutes to start the timer.
That puts a a timer in the toolbar where
we can see what's going on or how long we
have left,
and then once we're finished with our one
session, we can then do Bob next.
which uh
We'll then do a a commit if there were if
it finds any changes.
OK, buddy.
Yeah, I tried the mob start,
but it looks like I get a 403.
I tried it a few times since we've been
having some GitHub connection issues,
but it seems like it's the same and it's
403,
so it sounds like an authentication
problem.
Hmm.
I'd I'd put the error in the chat that
I'm getting.
Let me see it.
I think the issue.
Yeah,
is that I need to add you as a
collaborator.
Into the to the repo.
So let me do that. Can you paste?
Can you each paste in your GitHub user ID?
You were supposed to fork the repo, right?
You don't need to this repo.
You don't need to fork it.
You just need to be added as a
contributor because this doesn't affect
the classes repo.
I have another repo that we'll be using
tomorrow that we'll want to fork.
Yeah,
I must have misinterpreted that slide
then,
because I've been working off of a fork.
That might have been.
Well, that's fine. Oh, well,
you're gonna have to go back to the main
OK.
one and clone the main one.
Alright.
Love next. Looks like our mom is done.
All right, buddy, you're in.
Look for an invite.
OK, I'll I'll try it again.
Hey John, it's still doing it,
but I'm gonna give it a few minutes just
in case since there's some GitHub issues.
Alright.
Uh, Tom, I don't. I'm not seeing your.
User ID tell him.
ohh I'll check it again. Sorry.
I'm having an issue because um I have all
these uh pending changes after I change
branches.
Yeah.
Um.
Well, you can stash them.
OK.
So John, you can't see mine.
I'm this is what I see from my username.
Hello.
Was that not what you were asking for?
Yeah, I think so.
But when I let me try it again because
you know.
Do you know I was having issues?
It says it cannot find a GitHub account
matching Tom dash Booie under score MKSI.
That's what I'm saying.
Uh.
I think it.
Can you can you try Peters?
But Peter, are you using the one from the?
Yeah, I am.
Artwork.
Yep.
OK.
Just wondering if there's something. Yeah.
Hey Tom,
you could try maybe going to your profile
and then seeing the URL the the name in
your URL for your profile on GitHub that
that might that might work.
Um, OK, it says it's the same thing.
Would an e-mail address work as an
alternative?
It might.
OK, I'll give you my e-mail address too.
Yeah,
it it's showing up as the same username
when I go to my profile.
Hey John, it it worked for me this time.
It just took a little while. It's buddy.
Excuse me, it work.
Yeah, it it it worked for me.
It just took a few minutes I guess.
OK, all right, I'm working my way through.
Almost everybody has been invited.
And if you can't get mine to work,
I don't want to hold up the whole class.
You can continue on.
Yeah.
Is anybody else having trouble installing
mob?
Are you on Windows?
Yeah, Windows 11. I've tried Scoop,
I've tried Choco, I've.
Yeah, they're all broken.
The only one that worked for me was the
Ridiculous.
get bash. Do you have get bash installed?
I do. Let me try that.
Yeah, you could do.
You could try that one.
I think the other option which is
basically the same option is if if you
have a WSL,
you know like a a Linux distro or
Yeah, Yep. Yeah, I've had that. OK. Yeah,
I'll try those. Thanks, man.
something.
So um.
Yeah,
I tried the WSL install and I do not have
a mob start button.
Oh, I think that's a different extension,
right? John, the the buttons on the UI.
That's the that's the yeah,
but if you do the installation of mob dot
SH, it should add those buttons.
I had to install a extension on VS code
to for them to show up, but well,
I mean the commands still worked, yeah,
yeah.
Oh, you're right.
You're you're you're right. You're right.
Yeah.
That's correct. Thanks for making that.
I'll make a note to update the install.
OK,
so do the WSL steps and then add the
extension.
And then and then add the extension.
Oh.
Yeah.
Thank you.
I was able to get started.
So good.
Tom, yeah.
So the branch we should use is more
fundamentals or fundamentals?
Um.
Was the was the branch name we should use?
Fundamentals.
Just without the more prefix because I
that's what I see on screen MOB slash
continental.
Yeah, you talking about this one?
Yeah,
which which branch should we pick from
here?
Fundamentals, please.
But.
When you do mob start moves you to mob
slash fundamentals.
Can you repeat that?
When I was on the fundamentals branch,
I did mob star and then I was on the the
mob fundamentals branch.
I think that's just part of the operation.
All right. Um, so.
So one of us needs to start this and I
think publish the branch.
So I've started.
Are we supposed to be on Fundamentals or
Fundamentals Dash Baked?
Well,
we're going to be on this Fundamentals
Dash 3 when I get this posted.
All right,
there's you should see a branch now.
Called Bob Fundamentals Dash 3.
How do I get out of a mob session?
Because I accidentally ended up on the
main branch when I started.
Do a mob stop. We're done here.
OK. Thanks.
Alright,
who's uh still have issues with their?
but isn't clear about what we need to do.
So do we need to uh check out the
fundamentals 3 branch or or is or is mob
Yeah, check out. Yeah,
check out the fundamental 3 branch.
just gonna be used?
And then start mob. I already started mob,
so should I stop mob then?
Yeah,
stop the mob because only we only need to
start one mob and then we need to join
that branch and then we can do a mob mob
next from that point forward.
I don't seem to be pulling down a oh,
there it is.
Anybody else getting like a lot of files
from like the object debug and the bin
So it doesn't.
debug folder?
Looks like those got committed to the
Yeah, yeah, I just.
branch.
Just deleted those.
I don't know if I can push them,
I thought, but just delete them.
So John,
I was able to do mob start accidentally,
but mob done won't let me run it.
It's giving me permission issues.
Hmm.
This is not allowing me and it gives me
that credential pop up and and saying
unable to access 403 error.
Not sure if that's something on my end.
I just did a a mob start and it's looks
like it's staged a commit.
Those changes.
You said Bob stop STOP.
I'm all done.
Oh yeah.
So I've done a I did a mobs done and.
That looks like it's closed that branch,
so I'll do a mob start again and then
that should create a new branch that we
should switch to.
All right, so we're back on.
Fundamental C.
So who's on this branch?
Which one is that? I'm current.
I currently have Fundamentals 3 each
Right. All right. So can you, can you,
can you do a a mob next?
checked out and I didn't get. What's that?
See. No, I get an error permission. Sorry,
I'm logged in on the wrong GitHub.
Let me switch the GitHub account.
I got a 403 error.
I don't have permission to join.
Yeah.
John,
would you mind adding the username I just
put in as a collaborator also?
So.
That should be able to do a mob next
after that.
Um, didn't find that person.
It may be because it's a GitHub
enterprise.
All right, so.
Anybody else? Uh.
Yeah, I can't get in.
It says access denied to my account,
In.
which is DB Man 86.
OK, so I I have a thought.
Why don't why don't we abandon or skip
the tool?
I'll do all the driving and then we'll
just go through a rotation and I'll set
the timer here.
So I'll do all the mob next.
And I'll let everybody know when the
timer goes off.
And the benefits of the tool would be is
that it would everybody would hear the
timer go off and everybody would be able
to initiate their sessions.
But in lieu of that,
I think we can move forward with just
having.
Sharing this,
sharing my screen and and then going
through the exercises that does that make
sense?
Everyone apologize for the the tool.
I'm not sure whether it's the problems
with GitHub or something else, but.
Could you just give an overview of like
you know,
I don't know what Bob next means or mob
done or this or that like could you maybe
just give like an overview or you or you
just wanna show it as we go along?
Should.
Yep, same question.
OK, so just in brief, log next.
So the way this works is that we start a
session,
we all collaborate in that session one at
a time. So one person is driving.
Now if I started the the session then I
would be the first person driving.
The process. I share my screen.
Everybody can see what I'm doing,
except that I don't actually do anything
unless I'm told to do by the rest of the
group.
So the the rest of the group decides, OK,
what's the next thing we should do?
I type in whatever the the request is.
And then when my timer expires after that
working session,
I push the mob next button that commits
the changes to the work in progress
branch and then the next person can then
pull the work in progress branch.
They can click on mob.
Start and then now that would start them
on the their particular coding session
where they're driving and we move on,
you know,
person to person going through that
rotation until we're finished and that's
where the mob done would come in.
But in in lieu of that,
I'll do all of that work on my end.
You guys can share my screen.
And then what we'll do is we'll just
rotate through everybody. Actually,
you know,
we'll just basically everybody else can
tell me to or collaborate on what I
should be doing next, so.
Does that does that answer your question?
We'll get a sense of it, but.
So.
So it's like a peer programming sort of
thing it seems like.
It is like a pair, pair programming,
except with just instead of two people,
you have a whole group and everybody
rotates through the process of actually
typing at the computer versus, you know,
telling the person what to do next.
That's how it's supposed to work.
All right,
so I'm gonna go back just briefly to the
slides and then we'll then we'll get into
some of the coding pieces, so.
Real quick,
just I got an e-mail to confirm access to
the repo, so I don't know, maybe.
No, that's that's why you're getting.
That's why you're getting the 403 is.
Yeah, so that's probably why.
So just in case anybody else doesn't
realize that there should be an e-mail,
you need to accept the invitation.
All right,
we might we might give it another try
later on and see if we can get it to work,
but.
All right,
so So what I would like to do for the
rest of this afternoon is to collaborate
together on building a solution, right?
So the solution I have I've used that I
think works fairly well because everybody
understands the domain.
Is to create a basic calculator and then
add functionality to that calculator as
we're going going through the exercise.
So what I have here is a whole bunch of
things to suggest that we could do things
like adding certain features,
doing things like test automation,
dependency management.
And those kinds of things,
all all of this we can actually kind of
work our way through if we want and get
as much of it is is is done as we can get
done during the course of the afternoon.
See how far we can develop a solution
using AI assistance and some of this the
A I 1st and.
And particularly prompt first in this
exercise to try to to build out that that
application.
So here we're on this fundamental branch.
I can click mob start. I can say OK,
you know.
We'll do 3 minutes to start that.
And I've started my turn.
So the like question would be now what do
we want to if we're gonna build a
calculator, how do we,
what are the questions that we have to
ask before we get started on a calculator?
Any ideas?
It's gonna be basic scientific graphing.
Well,
let's start with basic and we can add
other things as well,
right as we go along.
What type of what type of UI framework
you wanna use?
So.
Stuff like like the the technology stack
that you wanna build it in?
To me.
All right, that's a that's good. Yeah,
I would start with the technology stack.
So what do we suggest for that?
Anybody having real preferences or we
just want to does C# work first for at
least some of the code?
Yes.
All right, so
Yeah, yes.
It's um.
How do we start with something like hello?
World.
How's that sound?
Mhm.
Sounds good.
All right,
so let's take a look at what we have here.
No.
C# file with our console right line for
Hello World. That's what we want.
We don't need that.
Looks like it's it's found my sample book
library app.
We need to get ignore. There are lots of.
They had that to ignore, get ignore,
right?
Yeah, so let's do that.
That's a good suggestion.
We did this earlier. Create a.
And we'll see start up application.
Oops.
Mob next. It fixed my console.
So, so we see here that it's um.
Created a git ignore file,
but if we look at this file which looks
fine for us.
Notice that we have these this keep an
undo message here.
So what copilot will do is for every
individual change it will allow us to
accept or undo those changes.
So here we see three different ways of
doing those this one.
Keeps just this one change here and there
is only one since it's new file.
This one will keep all of the changes
that were made in this file and this will
keep all of the changes that were made as
a result of this prompt.
Alright, so you can choose what level.
What's nice about this one is that if
you're if it's made a lot of different
small changes,
you can go through them one at a time and
you can evaluate them whether or not
they're what you want.
So let's go ahead and keep that so we
have that file in place.
And I don't see that it's.
Recognize these files.
Did it? Where did it put that?
Well.
That's um.
It says take these out. Oh,
it states this one file.
And so this little icon here lets us
generate a commits message, which is nice,
and it will do it for whatever you staged
if.
And so here we say that it added to get a
newer file.
I see here Ben and OBJ,
but maybe it is this.
Yeah,
I think you need star star in front of
Lab.
those.
With with the directory slash to there
you go.
Still not recognizing.
Let me add that.
Um.
All right, so push those changes. Oh,
I haven't pushed them yet, but.
What happened is to say add these files
to the.
Yeah.
And see if it can point me to the error
of my waves.
I have weird.
But anyway.
All right, so let's sync those changes.
You should now have an updated branch you
could pull the recent code from.
And um.
Hey, John,
just making sure we're on Fundamentals 3,
right?
That's what I'm on, Bob.
OK.
OK, cool.
All right, all right,
so we have a hello world file.
Where did it end up?
Under C#.
Here it is.
He's there.
Yeah.
All right, So what do we do next? I mean,
looks like we got we mixed this up with
another project,
so maybe we should create a separate
project.
What do you think?
A folder at least.
Right.
So.
Subfolder.
Oops.
OK, so we did that. So push our changes.
This is.
Think what I'm gonna do to just to make
it easier.
Yeah.
If I have those files somewhere else,
that should clean things U.
And.
Alright, so let's stage on that.
All right,
so unless you have a cleaner version of
this,
we shouldn't see those issues with the
object OBJ folders. All right, so.
What's next?
Yeah.
Anybody suggest a prompt?
We're working towards trying to build a
console application that can do some
basic arithmetic.
Uh, maybe?
You prompt the user for.
Log in.
So the when the console app first runs,
it would.
Prompt the user to enter in a
mathematical problem.
Um.
All right.
So for like an exact prompt,
maybe you know add a feature that when
the application first runs it prompts the.
The user for the mathematical question.
Is this used in the book library Csproj?
No, I took that.
I took basically you removed it from the
from the branch.
OK.
'Cause I've got two entry point,
two main entry points is 'cause I still
have a book library program file there.
Right.
All right, so here we have another one.
We have more than one change that was
made.
The first is added a a enter mathematical
expression line and the second one it's a
doing an evaluation of that expression.
Right.
So let's keep those changes with what do
you think we want to do next?
See if it works.
Yeah.
Have it write a test for evaluate
expression.
Alright, create a.
Alright,
so do we have now a expression tester?
And that's um.
So I wonder why it doesn't.
Alright, so keep that.
And saving the tests.
Hey John,
can you show your folder explorer real
quick just so we can see because I don't
think I have ACS proj.
Yeah,
that's what it's complaining about right
now.
Yeah.
It says there's no CS proj file.
So.
And it's good to do that then.
That sex.
What's that?
That's interesting. It chose net 6.
Hmm.
All right, so it wants.
It's telling us here that we want to
create a sensitive file and that we want
to allow that to happen. All right.
And then we did allow it per this
workspace,
but we're going to be doing this once.
What does allow in session do?
It's different from your workspace.
That means that, yeah,
this means that in in my current session
in Visual Studio.
It will allow it.
Right.
These the sessions that we're talking
about when we go into the the the chat
history.
Yeah, I think it would.
I think it'd be easier to upgrade it to
Net 8, John.
Right.
And um.
Yeah.
It.
He knows a six is out of support but have
created it anyway.
Let's go ahead and.
See if we can run the test now.
I.
So I'd asked it to use any unit and it's
updated the.
Project file.
Does it automatically push changes to git
or you do that manually?
Um, I could ask it to push the changes.
But you you were doing it manually so
hard.
It's interesting.
So far, yes.
So it's basically saying that Nuget,
there's no sources configured in Nuget.
Right.
Well,
actually it's better way of doing this.
Just say what? Um.
With my terminal option.
It's in there.
It.
Now this way we can attack this is say go
ahead and try to fix this problem.
So I'm saying terminal last command which
is allows it to look at the terminal.
So instructions for.
That's global settings.
You can do it for your projects locally.
You can create a Nugget with the desired
package map,
package source mapping as part of
solution.
So we had to create a solution.
Nugget config can be either global like
it suggests making changes in global or
Yeah.
you can make it your solution.
No good config, that's cool.
Hmm.
So what did it change?
Here's the new yet config.
So it wants us to, it wants to detect,
let's keep this version and let's go
ahead and say yes to.
Mhm.
This requests.
And so it's doing another net restore.
Still having problems?
Alright.
Um.
I'm not sure where I'll find that file.
Uh,
File Explorer will understand percent app
David percent.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah, I didn't know that. Thank you.
No.
All right. So now we go back and.
And remove or update any captured source
mapping.
Yeah, it's all that stuff,
all that junk down there.
That's here.
I'm curious,
like what's the advantage of using using
this instead of just like us sharing
another branch?
It seems like that's what it's doing.
Doesn't seem like we're doing anything
really that special with mob,
but am I missing something?
Well, that's all. I mean,
remote lobbing is the way it works is
that everybody who's going to be driving
would pull down that branch at the time
that there is that that start their
session and then when they're finished
they would push to the branch and the
next person would pull.
But since we're not doing that,
we don't need the we're not,
we're not changing drivers.
I'm doing all the driving and and we're
not really doing a rotation.
Does that make sense?
If we were able to do the rotation then
then I would drive for a little while and
then I would hand it to you.
And then you would drive and and.
It looks like the problem got worse.
Yeah, I mean, I get it. But like,
why do I? Why do I use this mob thing?
Like, why can't we just say, OK,
I just come to my changes next person,
just pull the latest and you go.
And I mean what?
You could read it.
I don't understand the advantage of this.
I'm just curious.
Uh.
We are. We could.
The only advantage is that it it it'll
handle it.
It handles the creation and the updating
of the branches.
You don't have to deal with the git and
the background.
It kind of does that for you, right?
So you you do you deal with multiple
branches as part of same process.
You don't need to jump individually from
1 branch to another if I understand.
No, no.
You have one branch and everybody pushes
to that same branch.
But.
Is it when what happens when you select
mob next that pushes push happens
automatically?
Yes.
OK,
so that that list makes things simpler
for from like workflow point of view.
If you instead of collaborating through
git, you just use mob API,
I mean mob controls like mob start,
Correct. That's correct. All right.
It was just a it's just to facilitate the
mob next.
Yeah.
the the transition from one person to the
to the to the next.
Are you even using it now, John? I mean,
you're just kind of pushing into your
branch anyways, right?
Yeah, correct.
And then we might try it again later on.
So are we still having Nugent issues here?
Yeah, we are.
Hey John,
would it be better if maybe we we try to
Yeah.
like just use the regular CLI dotnet
tools just to create the the the
boilerplate project and then and then we
start using the AI agent?
Yeah.
You know, why don't we do that?
I I notice that, yeah,
I notice sometimes it's just better to to
kind of get the the the tool like the ID
or the CLI to create it first.
Sure.
Yeah.
Yeah, like Writer or Visual Studio,
but this in the shape real quick.
All right, so.
So we want to start with a new empty
folder.
Why don't you drive me through what you
thinking you're doing?
So like just using the regular dotnetlike.
net new you know like project or or how
however you know we usually do it,
you know before AI you know like just
Right.
just to create the initial project.
And then then and then we can start using
the agent.
So.
So I should delete everything out of this
folder then.
Uh yeah,
or create a calculator too or whatever.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. The.
net has its own scaffolding built in.
Yep.
Like I've been doing a lot of Python
projects for like simple like tools and
I'm not a I'm not a Python developer and
I'll just tell I'll tell the agent hey
Oh.
can you help me create the project and
then it'll it'll give me all the commands.
You know that that's one one thing that
that that I've been doing.
Um.
Which kind of helps too,
but like it's still using, you know,
Yeah.
like the standard Python,
like how how a Python developer would set
it up. But yeah, something like that,
yeah.
It will use the name of, yeah, yeah,
that will work as well.
I know.
Rather.
All right.
All right, that's good.
So we have a project.
Let's get back on track, then.
Um.
So we said add a feature when any
application first runs.
So I went back to our original prompt,
changed it slightly and.
I'll give her a chance.
So it's taking out our hello world.
Yeah, it's calculating the expression.
So we can see here now it's asking for
our mathematical expression and we'll say
one plus.
And it tells us that we entered that.
And then the next thing we did, well,
we don't. We don't have here any.
A module to test or anything at this
point.
So what's the suggestion for the next
step?
Actually perform the evaluation.
All right.
All right, so.
You see that it out code to do that
expression.
We now have our evaluer expression.
If we were to run it again.
We get the prompts.
Oh, that looks like it's OK.
So what do we do next?
Can you run it with 1 / 0?
Infinity.
What do we do next?
Well, let's see.
Return back to Brittany.
Maybe, sorry.
I'm sorry.
Go ahead.
If you have a suggestion,
you should raise your hand and I can call
I was gonna say.
on you and that way we can queue them up.
Alright buddy.
Maybe we can make it what do you call it?
Like read rewind or you know where it
doesn't,
where you could just keep doing the
mathematical expressions.
Y'all know what I'm talking about like
the re reply or I can't remember what the
Sure.
Mhm.
acronym.
All right,
how would you phrase that as a prompt?
Yeah, that's what I'm trying.
I'm trying to think of what.
What would the you know what I mean?
Like an interactive or I guess we could
just ask it.
I want like an interactive make the
console app interactive and and don't
exit.
How do we uh?
You're saying keep the session open,
right?
Yeah, yeah.
So you can enter another mathematical
expression. So just a retry or a loop,
right? OK.
Yeah, that's what I was trying to.
There's like an acronym that some people
use. It's like a loop. Yeah,
like you're you're generating a loop.
Like you're reading the input. I mean,
I'm trying to look it up.
So I'm I'm asking just make the contour
after interactive.
Don't exit after evaluating your
expression.
Yeah, we'll see.
We'll see if it does what I'm talking
about.
All right.
All right,
let's keep that and see what it does.
Well, looks like we got a warning.
About a null per type, so 1 + 1.
And divided by zero.
So that's working.
So what do I wanna do next?
How do you quit?
The question.
So add code to be able to quit.
OK.
Says Tye exit to quit.
Mhm.
Oh, oh, yeah, at the top it did. Yeah.
Thanks.
Yep.
Well, it's interesting, you know,
we asked it to do that and it figured out
or inferred that we needed a way to get
out of the app and it provided it.
So what do we think about next?
Here's some ideas we have. Well,
we can say let's put a UI around it so we
can.
Oops.
What is the technology we would want the
UI to be in?
I'll do a push so guys can catch up.
Any buddy, you have a question?
Suggestion.
Sorry, my mic was still muted.
I I guess since we're we might not all be
on Windows,
I guess we'll just stick with a web
interface, right?
All right.
Not sure what it wants.
An emty workspace folder.
So it wants to build another project.
I guess that would make sense, right?
Since this is a console project.
Yeah.
Here it's this time it's decided it
wanted to do a.net now.
So what's this?
There we go.
To creating our GitHub folder.
All right, so.
We have our program CS,
so let's keep that.
There are the projects.
I'm not mistaken,
you named your directory calculator dash
web, but it's doing web dash calculator.
You know.
Am I in the wrong folder?
I think there's this sub folder of web
dash calculator you should run it from.
So there's another folder on this one
you're saying.
Yeah.
All right, so we can launch our app.
All right. Everybody happy with that?
We got some new I we didn't ask for.
All right, so um.
Anybody got a suggestion?
How about that?
A clear button.
So I see our button.
We've updated uh on posts.
So go ahead and run this one.
And still the wrong folder.
I think we're still running a service.
All right, so we have a clear button.
Yeah, Chris.
Do we have any tests yet of the engine
written?
No, we don't. You wanna ride some toasts?
I want AI to.
All righty.
OK.
Unauthorized.
It's got a build failure that it needs to
fix.
So how we want to deal with this is was
expecting it to throw exception if we try
to evaluate a empty string.
We should probably adjust.
The calculator to handle emty strings.
Dh,
I will say modify the calculator to
handle empty strings.
Here we see it throwing an exception.
So it wants to update the app to change
how the exception is handled.
Good.
So we got we're working in all the tests
are passing.
You run the app.
Hopefully evaluate this.
We get our exception.
We can ask you to handle that exception.
One.
Mm.
All right. So that looks good. All right.
So we didn't get as far into this as I
was hoping,
but I still want to do one more thing
before we go for the day. So let me.
close this all and let's I wanna try one
thing.
So I have to bring up the workspace.
To redo the code.
And and uh, let's there it is.
Not ever.
No.
So Evergreen is is basically the idea
that once you write the code,
it's it's a Greenfield and what we want
to do is keep it Greenfield going forward.
So what this is doing is looking at the
code that we've already written and
saying where it sees problems that would
limit the maintainability or would not be
the way that we would like we would write
a different review writing it complete.
From scratch.
So in a sense the work that we we're
doing is essentially adding technical
debt to the project and essentially our
our effort in the Greenfield development
is turning brownfield very quickly.
So you can see here it identified you
know.
Six different things that would would be
improvements on it that would make it
more Evergreen,
more maintainable over time.
So we, you know,
explicit package versions, hardcoding.
net versions, static URLs and ports.
Some of these things we would want to try
to address to try to keep it.
Evergreen and if we were able to far go a
little bit farther into this exercise,
we would have seen that.
Um.
We would have seen even we would have
seen even more issues than we were seeing
here so so far.
So the So what I want to get into
tomorrow starting with the brownfield
course is talking about Evergreen
development and how to to use the the
concepts of Evergreen development and.
To move on a a brownfield code base
closer to being Evergreen and closer to
being what we would write if we were to
write it from scratch today using modern
tooling,
modern technologies and we'll get into
techniques then to actually.
Get AI to help us implement those things
so and even take a look at how we can
have it continually monitor our code base
for where for areas where it's not,
you know,
it's deviation deviating from the concept
of Evergreen.
And and allow us to either you know break
the build if if we're introducing things
that would drift away from code from
Evergreen or to you know create issues
that we can use to then address those
those failings.
So a normal, you know,
backlog grooming process.
All right. So any any questions on?
What we're doing so far?
All right, well,
let's see if we can continue our process
of getting one or two more features into
this app before we go.
How about let's add?
Uh, buttons.
Mm.
Uh, for the digits.
and
Alright.
So here we can see here it added a bunch
of buttons into the page.
Still needs to kill that process.
Alright.
Now we're missing.
The basic arithmetic buttons.
Oops.
All right,
so it seems like that's working all right.
So we have 5 minutes left.
What other features do they think we can
get done?
How about um?
Oh, decimal support.
We're going to the app and say.
Plus.
Alright.
Yeah, we can't enter a period.
We can type it. Push it in this way.
Can handle the consumers but.
Allow decibel input from the keyboard.
Well, it says it can do it, but I tried.
I guess I could.
Alright, how about add?
And here we say add us percentage button.
It should infer that we're actually
wanted to actually calculate that as well.
So, all right.
So tomorrow we're going to get into
brownfield.
We'll start off with talking about
Evergreen and we'll talk quite a bit
about how we can what Evergreen is and
how we can actually move towards it.
And and then we'll get into a a lot of
work we're talking about to how to
refactor existing code bases,
some of the techniques that we can use to.
To understand the existing code base and
understand how we can go forward
modifying those those existing code bases
safely.
So I see here in our app and refresh it.
Missing our percentage.
There we go. All right.
That's it for today.
I'll see you tomorrow and then we'll pick
it up from there.
Thank you very much and I hope it was
useful.
Thanks, John.
Thank you.
Next.
Hi, everyone.
Goodbye.